<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sørens Code|Speak</title><link>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/</link><description>Recent posts from on Sørens Code|Speak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The ∨∑ (orsum) new toy language</title><link>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/post/first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/post/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let me start this first post by explaining a little about what to expect in this blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the--orsum-new-toy-language">The ∨∑ (orsum) new toy language&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I am not a professional programmer. In fact, I have never finished any significant piece of software outside of small, closed, academic circles. I am a physicist. And I have written loads of one-off analysis software within mathematics, physics, and computer vision. I like programming. I enjoy trying new programming languages, just to see if they are more suited for various tasks. And until a few years ago, I never imagined that I could make one myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I stumbled onto one of Jon Blows presentations about Jai&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>: A Programming Language for Games. It occurred to me: perhaps building my own language is not &lt;em>completely&lt;/em> impossible. And so I began planning my own programming language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a heavy C++ and Python user. Naturally, I want to make something at least as good as either of those. Still, I will try fixing some stuff I know can be improved. Right from the start, I knew this language was going to be a systems language. Not so much because I wanted to build OS&amp;rsquo;s or anything like that. But because system languages always felt &lt;em>right&lt;/em> to me. The explicity and power always drew me in. However, I also do not want to forget about mathematical analysis nor the ability to quickly prototype something. I started to compile my own wish list:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My programming language must be:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a systems language,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a mathematical language,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a &lt;em>scribbling&lt;/em> language, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>an easy language.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Many, including myself, will see a lot of conflicts in the above goals. But I wanna try it out! That is what this blog is all about. During the development process, I also hope to write tutorials, research, notes, and ideas. Anything, really, that could be interesting to write about (within programming).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-name">The name?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Of course, I cannot embark on this adventure without a name. After some hefty debate with fellow scientists and programming enthusiasts, we came up with nothing. Finally, we gave up. We did agree, however, that whatever the name will be, it should be &lt;em>awesome&lt;/em>. And that is what we called it&amp;hellip; ∨∑ (orsum). And I have to say, to be able to call the source code &amp;lsquo;∨∑ source&amp;rsquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. That just sounds right.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>Blow, Jonathan, 2014, A Programming Language for Games, accessed 06 September 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLmV5I2fxaiCKfxMBrNsU1kgKJXD3PkyxO">https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLmV5I2fxaiCKfxMBrNsU1kgKJXD3PkyxO&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>With my Danish accent, it really sounds like saying &lt;em>awesome sauce&lt;/em>.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>