<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on Sørens Code|Speak</title><link>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on Sørens Code|Speak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/about/</guid><description>About My name is Søren K.S. Gregersen. I am an engineer schooled in physics and nanotechnology. I tried pursuing an academic career in nano electronics and later computer vision (see my old work at Google scholar). Now, however, I am employed as a imaging systems engineer in the medical industry. I consider myself a more-than-a-hobbyist programmer with many unfinished projects (see my random code at Github).
About this blog This is where I collect my general thoughts on programming, languages, tools, and frameworks.</description></item><item><title>The ∨∑ (orsum) new toy language</title><link>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/post/first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sksg.github.io/codespeak/post/first-post/</guid><description>Let me start this first post by explaining a little about what to expect in this blog.
The ∨∑ (orsum) new toy language I am not a professional programmer. In fact, I have never finished any significant piece of software outside of small, closed, academic circles. I am a physicist. And I have written loads of one-off analysis software within mathematics, physics, and computer vision. I like programming. I enjoy trying new programming languages, just to see if they are more suited for various tasks.</description></item></channel></rss>